Guide to the Ben Rosen Papers, 1936-2006 and undated, bulk 1945-1991
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic Materials Series, 1946-1990 and undated [RESTRICTED], (3 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Clients (graphic design and packaging)
      - Philip Morris
        - Packaging for chewing tobacco (Old Delft, Field and Stream), circa 1960s
          - Cigarettes
            - Holiday cartons (Marlboro, Alpine, Philip Morris King Size), circa 1960s (Box 65)
            - Package concepts, Various, circa 1960s (Box 65)
          - Cigars
            - Benson & Hedges (Gold Band, Merit), circa 1960s (Box 65)
        - Publication, Call News front page, 1966 (Box 65)
      - Pleetway (sleepwear), undated (Box 65)
      - Shell Oil Co., antifreeze can packaging, undated (Box 65)
      - Sky Chef, Good Morning menus, 1946 (Box 65)
      - Tishman Realty and Construction (Horizon House, Tower East), undated (Box 65)
      - Various
        - Blaine Thompson clients, beauty products, 1947-1948 (Box 65)
        - Other, undated (Box 65)
          Includes Carstairs Whiskey, Trommer's Beer, Simon's.
    - Original artwork, undated (Box 65)
      Includes family portraits and studies of paintings by prominent artists such as Klimt, Homer, Stella, and Leonardo.
    - unidentified research materials, undated (Box 65)
  - Slides
    - Ben Rosen Associates, undated, (2 folders) (Box 66)
    - Books
      - Corporate Search for Visual Identity, 1971 and undated, (2 folders) (Box 66)
      - Type and Typography, 1971 (Box 66)
    - Clients
      - American Loose Leaf, undated (Box 66)
      - Art Crayon Company, 1959, 1979 and undated (Box 66)
      - Asgrow Mandeville, undated (Box 66)
      - Ben-Mont Papers, factory approach signs/packaging, 1958-1959 (Box 66)
      - Check Card Systems (CCS/ICS), presentations/designs, undated (Box 66)
      - Creative Tools, Easydriver mini screwdrivers, undated (Box 66)
      - (Dorset Laboratories Dorset/Toole), undated, (3 folders) (Box 66)
      - Exxon, undated, (3 folders) (Box 66)
      - Gilbarco, 1979 and undated, (7 folders) (Box 66)
      - IBM, undated, (2 folders) (Box 66)
      - Montclair, undated (Box 66)
      - North American Reinsurance, undated (Box 66)
      - Philip Morris, undated, (8 folders) (Box 67)
      - Pleetway, undated (Box 67)
      - Richardson-Merrill (Richardson-Vicks), undated (Box 67)
      - Russ Berrie, undated, (7 folders) (Box 67)
      - Sky Chef, undated (Box 67)
      - Standard Brands (Royal Baking Powder), undated (Box 67)
      - Tishman Realty and Construction, undated, (2 folders) (Box 67)
      - United Nations Association, USA 1956 (Box 67)
      - Various
        - Alcoholic beverage holiday packaging (Smirnoff Vodka, Carstairs Whisky, Park & Tilford Whisky), undated (Box 67)
        - Beauty/Cosmetics, undated (Box 67)
        - Book jackets/exhibits, undated (Box 67)
        - Miscellaneous, circa early 1950s (Box 67)
          Includes Jersey-Millbrook, Karo syrup, National Pharmaceuticals, and Pepperell sheets.